<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Cooking on Alexander Kucera</title>
    <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/categories/cooking/</link>
    <description></description>
    
    <language>de</language>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 10:30:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Productivity Conversation I Didn&#39;t Expect to Have</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2025/06/21/the-productivity-conversation-i-didnt.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2025/06/21/the-productivity-conversation-i-didnt.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I sat down to write about productivity. Instead, I accidentally solved my productivity problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started with a simple request. I wanted to turn my struggles with overwhelm and chronic illness into a blog post. Multiple interests pulling me in different directions, dialysis eating up twelve hours a week, YouTube consumption replacing creation - the usual productivity paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You read more about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://alexanderkucera.com/2025/06/19/pulled-in-too-many-directions.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But something unexpected happened during the conversation with my AI writing assistant. What began as research for a blog post became a real-time case study in how productive conversations actually work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-original-problem&#34;&gt;The Original Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setup was familiar to anyone who&amp;rsquo;s ever felt overwhelmed by their own interests. I love coding, cooking, RPGs, fitness, reading. My wife has projects that need my support. I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be working on an iPad app for her. But instead of making progress on any of it, I find myself watching YouTube videos for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d even found a video that perfectly explained the problem - how our brains get hijacked by consumption, how creation provides more sustainable dopamine hits, how shifting from consumer to contributor changes everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/R4MInIP2c-A?si=rW29vhDlEfG-JAx7&#34;&gt;The Habit that forces your brain to stop consuming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understood the theory. I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t implement it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-conversation-that-changed-everything&#34;&gt;The Conversation That Changed Everything&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s your top priority right then?&amp;rdquo; came the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Probably the iPadOS app, since finishing that would help my wife greatly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple question. Clear answer. But then something interesting happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Those twelve hours of dialysis per week? That&amp;rsquo;s actually prime iPad development time. You could queue up iOS tutorials, work on app wireframes&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, there&amp;rsquo;s no Xcode for iPad,&amp;rdquo; I replied. &amp;ldquo;And my left arm is completely blocked with needles. I can&amp;rsquo;t move it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sudden silence. Then: &amp;ldquo;Right, of course there&amp;rsquo;s no Xcode for iPad. That was a pretty big oversight on my part.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-made-this-conversation-different&#34;&gt;What Made This Conversation Different&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most productivity advice fails because it&amp;rsquo;s generic. It assumes everyone has the same constraints, the same energy levels, the same physical capabilities. The conversation became productive the moment my real constraints got acknowledged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No judgment about not being able to code one-handed during medical treatment. No generic advice about &amp;ldquo;just managing your time better.&amp;rdquo; Instead: &amp;ldquo;What can you realistically do one-handed on an iPad for four hours?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The questions kept getting more specific:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What does your energy level look like after dialysis?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;When are you actually at your Mac with both arms free?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What makes this app section so complicated?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each question revealed another layer of reality that typical productivity advice ignores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lessons-hidden-in-the-dialogue&#34;&gt;The Lessons Hidden in the Dialogue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assumptions get corrected quickly.&lt;/strong&gt; The Xcode-on-iPad suggestion was wrong, but it got corrected immediately instead of becoming the foundation for useless advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constraints clarify priorities.&lt;/strong&gt; Once we established that dialysis time wasn&amp;rsquo;t coding time, it became clear that the real development work had to happen during my four productive in-between days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specificity beats generality.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Work on the app&amp;rdquo; is overwhelming. &amp;ldquo;Identify the next three concrete actions for the app&amp;rdquo; is actionable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions matter more than answers.&lt;/strong&gt; The breakthrough didn&amp;rsquo;t come from advice. It came from questions that helped me see my situation more clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-meta-lesson&#34;&gt;The Meta-Lesson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I realized: the conversation itself was demonstrating the productivity principle I needed to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of consuming more productivity content, I was actively working through my specific situation. Instead of generic advice, I was getting targeted questions. Instead of feeling judged for my limitations, I was finding ways to work with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversation was creation, not consumption. It was collaborative problem-solving in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-breakthrough-moment&#34;&gt;The Breakthrough Moment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real breakthrough came when we identified that the missing section of the app wasn&amp;rsquo;t just technically complicated - it was &amp;ldquo;lots of different pieces.&amp;rdquo; Suddenly the overwhelm made sense. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t one elegant problem to solve, but fifteen mini-features that all needed to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What if you just listed all the different pieces first? Not designing them, not coding them - just creating an inventory.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s when it clicked. The paralysis wasn&amp;rsquo;t about not knowing how to code. It was about not knowing where to start when everything felt connected to everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-this-means-for-productivity&#34;&gt;What This Means for Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best productivity hack might be finding someone who asks better questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not someone who gives you a system to follow. Not someone who tells you to eliminate distractions. Someone who helps you see your actual constraints clearly, then works with those constraints instead of ignoring them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generic productivity advice is like generic medical advice - it might work for some people, but it&amp;rsquo;s useless if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t account for your specific situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real productivity breakthrough happens when you stop trying to fit your life into someone else&amp;rsquo;s system and start building a system that fits your actual life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ironic-ending&#34;&gt;The Ironic Ending&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this conversation wanting to write about my productivity problems. I ended up actually solving them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blog post was supposed to be about the problem. Instead, it became about the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the most productive thing you can do is have a better conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2025/04/07/maybe-al-forno-instead-of.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 11:18:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2025/04/07/maybe-al-forno-instead-of.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe al forno instead of alla panna. Everything is better with a golden brown cheese topping.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2025/04/07/im-thinking-tortellini-alla-panna.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 10:29:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2025/04/07/im-thinking-tortellini-alla-panna.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m thinking tortellini alla panna for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Image courtesy of MidJourney)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://eu.uploads.micro.blog/239/2025/image-20250407-102902-e37a67ee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2025/04/06/we-had-a-really-nice.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 14:20:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2025/04/06/we-had-a-really-nice.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had a really nice Sunday dinner. Potatoes fluffed with parsley and butter, cauliflower and white asparagus. Topped with some honey glazed ham and loads of homemade hollandaise sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Image courtesy of MidJourney since I was too slow to take a picture before the family gobbled everything up.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://eu.uploads.micro.blog/239/2025/image-20250406-142039-b6e1103b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2025/01/04/making-crumpets-crumpets-where-one.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 15:11:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2025/01/04/making-crumpets-crumpets-where-one.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Making Crumpets. Crumpets where one of the first UK „treats“ I fell in love with when I first worked in Manchester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://eu.uploads.micro.blog/239/2025/64cc45ec-5eec-415c-8b27-181768d07d8f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2024/11/16/die-kommunionskinder-haben.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 13:12:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2024/11/16/die-kommunionskinder-haben.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Die Kommunionskinder haben heute Brot gebacken. Und wir Eltern sind jetzt da um es zu essen. Ich bin gespannt was serviert wird.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2024/11/07/making-some-feta.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:23:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2024/11/07/making-some-feta.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Making some feta in the oven. Yummy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2024/09/25/todays-lunch-homemade.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 13:47:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2024/09/25/todays-lunch-homemade.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s lunch: homemade beef and veggie soup with maultaschen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soooo delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No image today. Soup was gone faster then I was able to pull out my iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2024/09/24/im-thinking-crispy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 10:27:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2024/09/24/im-thinking-crispy.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I‘m thinking crispy fried potatoes with spinach, topped with a fried egg for today‘s lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Image courtesy of MidJourney)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://eu.uploads.micro.blog/239/2024/9778968da4.png&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;336&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2024/09/19/todays-lunch-zrcher.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 09:46:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2024/09/19/todays-lunch-zrcher.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today‘s lunch: Zürch‘er Geschnetzeltes with rice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Image courtesy of MidJourney)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://eu.uploads.micro.blog/239/2024/3158a76118.png&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;336&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2024/06/28/heute-mittag-gibts.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:45:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2024/06/28/heute-mittag-gibts.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Heute Mittag gibt’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/NaBqhLegW7E?si=KauI2ORRQRcddIG1&#34;&gt;Melonensalat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2024/04/03/whats-for-dinner.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 11:05:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2024/04/03/whats-for-dinner.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What’s for dinner? For us it’s steak with buttered veggies and rice. 🍚🥩🥕&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Image courtesy of MidJourney)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://eu.uploads.micro.blog/239/2024/616bb710b9.jpg&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>