<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Transcripts on Alexander Kucera</title>
    <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/transcripts/</link>
    <description></description>
    
    <language>de</language>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:07:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workout Done</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/transcripts/2024/11/08/1626.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 12:07:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexanderkucera.com/transcripts/2024/11/08/1626.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Done with today&amp;rsquo;s workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It went pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to today&amp;rsquo;s lunch, which will be steak with potatoes and some kind of veggie I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided on yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chorona Chor in der Kirche Geinsheim</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/transcripts/2024/09/07/1466.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 18:09:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexanderkucera.com/transcripts/2024/09/07/1466.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Auf deinem Himmel, den du aus deinem Himmel geboren bist, lass ich dich auf den Händen tragen, auf deinen Brusten, den du aus deinem Himmel geboren bist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lass ich dich auf den Händen tragen, lass ich dich auf den Händen tragen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 1</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/transcripts/2024/09/04/1459.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 09:19:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexanderkucera.com/transcripts/2024/09/04/1459.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi and welcome to the Babylon Dreams cast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Alexander Kucera and this is a little experiment in podcasting or microcasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m probably going to upload two or three episodes in the next few days since I&amp;rsquo;m attending FMX and that presents a good opportunity to just try this out and see how it goes and if it&amp;rsquo;s fun for me and maybe if anyone is listening they can let me know if it&amp;rsquo;s fun for them and then we&amp;rsquo;ll go from there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 5 - Prepping the vrscene GUI Intro Video</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/transcripts/2024/02/23/916.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:17:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexanderkucera.com/transcripts/2024/02/23/916.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in the office, prepping recording for my introductory video for vrcngui, the V-Way render utility I&amp;rsquo;m about to release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;m mostly, let&amp;rsquo;s see, yeah, working in Modo right now, trying to figure out from old backups which scenes are best suited for this type of video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need something that&amp;rsquo;s heavy and takes a long time to open and just generally a long time to export just to really show the point of the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m just opening huge scenes, waiting for them to open, staring at loading screens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to have Lauren Thomas do the voiceover for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s graciously offered that and I&amp;rsquo;m very excited to hear what she&amp;rsquo;s doing with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her Pixel Fondue tutorial videos are always quite peppy and I like her style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yes, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to hearing that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from that, the app&amp;rsquo;s finished, the website&amp;rsquo;s finished, documentation is pretty much finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, the only thing missing is really the video and contacting some websites for promotions and press releases and stuff like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to get that out next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been saying that for the past several weeks, but still the hope&amp;rsquo;s there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, let&amp;rsquo;s see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I know I&amp;rsquo;ve been not really regular with these recordings, but that&amp;rsquo;s mostly because I just don&amp;rsquo;t want to waste anybody&amp;rsquo;s time just blabbering into the mic just to have blabbered into the mic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My life isn&amp;rsquo;t that exciting that I have to record everything once a week or something like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That seems wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m reserving these two times when I actually have something to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All right, hear you soon, I guess, or whatever the appropriate goodbye is in audio form.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode 2 - FMX Day 1</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/transcripts/2023/08/11/383.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alexanderkucera.com/transcripts/2023/08/11/383.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s the second day at FMX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m driving down there to Stuttgart right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Tuesday, was the first day and it was, well, I mean, the conference itself was a little bit lukewarm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everybody I spoke to wasn&amp;rsquo;t too excited about all the talks that were scheduled yesterday, and it was true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, there were okay talks, but nothing major or nothing that stood out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, the main event for me and for a lot of others was to just meet old colleagues and new potential acquaintances and just stand around in the halls and chat and having lunch and going out for a drink afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that each year, the longer I go, the less important or less interesting the talks become, and the more interesting and more important to me personally are the interpersonal connections of meeting old friends and old colleagues and just discussing all the nerdy stuff that we all have in common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s great to just talk about visual effects and grading and compositing and Oculus and depth recording and VR and AR and all the other stuff that usually you just get blank stares from your neighbors or any other people in your surrounding area if you&amp;rsquo;re not just living in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s great to have an outlet for a week to just extensively talk about all the nerdy crazy shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today, day two, is looking a little bit more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a virtual humans track in Gloria on the whole morning, which I&amp;rsquo;m probably going to attend to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also some talk about using Substance Designer in visual effects production, which I&amp;rsquo;m trying to catch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the first thing in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If traffic flows through as smoothly as it does at the moment, I&amp;rsquo;ll have no problem catching that, but fingers crossed on that one, because I&amp;rsquo;m really interested in Substance Designer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I want to use it more for my own work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t really used it as much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve dabbled with it a bit, but texturing and all that stuff is very interesting to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m going to check that out and hope that it&amp;rsquo;s good, and not just a half-hour commercial of how great Substance is, and something with a little bit more meat would be nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked at the program this afternoon yet, but experience shows that no matter how you plan out your day, by noon the whole plan gets overthrown anyway, because you talk to people and hear about talks they find interesting, and then maybe also hear about talks you didn&amp;rsquo;t even notice in the schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, naturally, you just reschedule your whole afternoon anyways, or just tag along with other people, just to keep chatting away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m not too locked in on that yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>