<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Workout on Alexander Kucera</title>
    <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/categories/workout/</link>
    <description></description>
    
    <language>de</language>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 21:25:05 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>From 10 Meters to 1.5 Kilometers</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2025/06/21/from-meters-to-kilometers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 21:25:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2025/06/21/from-meters-to-kilometers.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eight weeks ago, I had open kidney surgery. After being bedridden for most of my three and a half week hospital stay, that final week felt like a triumph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d graduated from assisted walking to making it down the hospital floor and back on my own. By discharge day, I was walking the entire floor independently. I felt confident. Ready to get back to normal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That confidence lasted exactly ten meters outside the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten meters from my front door, I needed a thirty-second break. Just ten meters. The same distance I&amp;rsquo;d been covering easily in the hospital corridors suddenly felt impossible. After feeling so capable walking those hospital floors, I felt like I&amp;rsquo;d run a marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of that first day home, I&amp;rsquo;d managed maybe thirty or forty meters total before admitting complete defeat. The difference between hospital walking and real-world walking hit me like a wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand then. Hospital floors are designed for recovery. They&amp;rsquo;re flat, climate-controlled, with handrails and places to rest every few meters. The real world has curbs, uneven pavement, weather, and distances that actually matter. Walking a hospital corridor doesn&amp;rsquo;t prepare you for walking to your mailbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The medical reality is pretty straightforward, but no one really prepares you for the psychological whiplash. After weeks of bed rest followed by successful hospital walking, you think you&amp;rsquo;re ready. Then you discover that three and a half weeks of lying still, even with that final week of corridor walking, has fundamentally changed what your body can handle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those first few days home were a study in humility I never wanted to take. Each day I&amp;rsquo;d try to walk a little further. Some days I managed it. Other days I didn&amp;rsquo;t. The frustrating part wasn&amp;rsquo;t just the physical limitation—it was accepting that my hospital confidence had been completely misplaced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started tracking my progress. Not with meters or fancy apps, but with houses. How many houses down the street could I make it before needing a breather? Before I had to turn around? These landmarks became my measuring stick. When my confidence was shattered, making it one house further was concrete proof I was still getting better, even if it didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The breakthrough came gradually, then suddenly. Around week four post-surgery, I realized I wasn&amp;rsquo;t counting steps anymore. Week six, I was walking around the block. Week seven, I made it to the local park and back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I walked 1.5 kilometers in thirty minutes without stopping once. I held a conversation the entire time. Eight weeks after surgery, four and a half weeks after that humbling ten-meter reality check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What strikes me most isn&amp;rsquo;t just the physical progress. It&amp;rsquo;s how hospital walking creates false confidence that real-world recovery quickly corrects. Before surgery, walking was just transportation. Now it&amp;rsquo;s proof that my body works outside controlled environments. Each step feels like a small victory over both the surgery and that initial confidence crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research says most open surgery patients don&amp;rsquo;t hit these milestones until week ten or twelve, especially after extended hospital stays. That feels good to hear, but it also makes me realize how misleading hospital walking can be. Your real recovery timeline starts when you leave the building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re starting your own walking recovery after major surgery and hospitalization, here&amp;rsquo;s what I wish someone had told me. Hospital walking is just the beginning. Don&amp;rsquo;t let that final week of corridor confidence fool you into thinking you&amp;rsquo;re ready for the real world. You&amp;rsquo;re not, and that&amp;rsquo;s completely normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track everything once you&amp;rsquo;re home. Write down distances, times, how you felt. After that initial confidence crash, the numbers become your proof of progress when your brain tells you you&amp;rsquo;re moving backwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t compare your home walking to your hospital walking. They&amp;rsquo;re completely different activities requiring different energy levels and skills. Hospital floors are recovery training wheels. Real-world walking is the actual test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consistency beats intensity every single time. I walked every day after discharge, even if it was just to the mailbox. Those tiny daily efforts compound faster than sporadic longer attempts. Your body needs to relearn movement in real environments, not just controlled hospital corridors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad days will happen. Last week I had a terrible walking day where everything felt harder than usual. I questioned whether I was actually improving or just fooling myself. The next day I walked further than ever before. Recovery after that kind of confidence crash isn&amp;rsquo;t linear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mental side of this recovery taught me things I never expected to learn. Humility, for one. Hospital walking had made me feel capable. Real-world walking reminded me I was still healing. Both were necessary parts of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also taught me to celebrate ridiculously small victories. Making it to the corner without stopping. Walking up three stairs without getting winded. Holding a conversation while moving. After that ten-meter wake-up call, these became genuine achievements worth acknowledging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, I&amp;rsquo;m still technically in the recovery window. Open surgery patients don&amp;rsquo;t hit full recovery until month three. That means I&amp;rsquo;ve got another month of potential improvement ahead of me. The thought is both exciting and surreal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My new goal is two kilometers by week ten. Then maybe three by month three. But honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m less focused on the numbers now. The real victory is that walking feels normal again, even outside hospital corridors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recovery from major surgery isn&amp;rsquo;t just about getting back to where you were. It&amp;rsquo;s about developing a completely different appreciation for what your body can do in real environments, not just controlled ones. Every day I can walk 1.5 kilometers is a day I don&amp;rsquo;t take for granted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight weeks ago, that confident hospital walking meant nothing when faced with ten real meters. Today, 1.5 kilometers feels routine. That&amp;rsquo;s not just physical healing—that&amp;rsquo;s rebuilding trust with your own body one step at a time, in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post documents my personal recovery experience. Always follow your doctor&amp;rsquo;s specific instructions for post-surgery activity and recovery timelines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Productivity Conversation I Didn&#39;t Expect to Have</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2025/06/21/the-productivity-conversation-i-didnt.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2025/06/21/the-productivity-conversation-i-didnt.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I sat down to write about productivity. Instead, I accidentally solved my productivity problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started with a simple request. I wanted to turn my struggles with overwhelm and chronic illness into a blog post. Multiple interests pulling me in different directions, dialysis eating up twelve hours a week, YouTube consumption replacing creation - the usual productivity paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You read more about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://alexanderkucera.com/2025/06/19/pulled-in-too-many-directions.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But something unexpected happened during the conversation with my AI writing assistant. What began as research for a blog post became a real-time case study in how productive conversations actually work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-original-problem&#34;&gt;The Original Problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setup was familiar to anyone who&amp;rsquo;s ever felt overwhelmed by their own interests. I love coding, cooking, RPGs, fitness, reading. My wife has projects that need my support. I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be working on an iPad app for her. But instead of making progress on any of it, I find myself watching YouTube videos for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d even found a video that perfectly explained the problem - how our brains get hijacked by consumption, how creation provides more sustainable dopamine hits, how shifting from consumer to contributor changes everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/R4MInIP2c-A?si=rW29vhDlEfG-JAx7&#34;&gt;The Habit that forces your brain to stop consuming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understood the theory. I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t implement it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-conversation-that-changed-everything&#34;&gt;The Conversation That Changed Everything&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s your top priority right then?&amp;rdquo; came the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Probably the iPadOS app, since finishing that would help my wife greatly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple question. Clear answer. But then something interesting happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Those twelve hours of dialysis per week? That&amp;rsquo;s actually prime iPad development time. You could queue up iOS tutorials, work on app wireframes&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, there&amp;rsquo;s no Xcode for iPad,&amp;rdquo; I replied. &amp;ldquo;And my left arm is completely blocked with needles. I can&amp;rsquo;t move it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sudden silence. Then: &amp;ldquo;Right, of course there&amp;rsquo;s no Xcode for iPad. That was a pretty big oversight on my part.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-made-this-conversation-different&#34;&gt;What Made This Conversation Different&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most productivity advice fails because it&amp;rsquo;s generic. It assumes everyone has the same constraints, the same energy levels, the same physical capabilities. The conversation became productive the moment my real constraints got acknowledged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No judgment about not being able to code one-handed during medical treatment. No generic advice about &amp;ldquo;just managing your time better.&amp;rdquo; Instead: &amp;ldquo;What can you realistically do one-handed on an iPad for four hours?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The questions kept getting more specific:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What does your energy level look like after dialysis?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;When are you actually at your Mac with both arms free?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What makes this app section so complicated?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each question revealed another layer of reality that typical productivity advice ignores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lessons-hidden-in-the-dialogue&#34;&gt;The Lessons Hidden in the Dialogue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assumptions get corrected quickly.&lt;/strong&gt; The Xcode-on-iPad suggestion was wrong, but it got corrected immediately instead of becoming the foundation for useless advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constraints clarify priorities.&lt;/strong&gt; Once we established that dialysis time wasn&amp;rsquo;t coding time, it became clear that the real development work had to happen during my four productive in-between days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specificity beats generality.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Work on the app&amp;rdquo; is overwhelming. &amp;ldquo;Identify the next three concrete actions for the app&amp;rdquo; is actionable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questions matter more than answers.&lt;/strong&gt; The breakthrough didn&amp;rsquo;t come from advice. It came from questions that helped me see my situation more clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-meta-lesson&#34;&gt;The Meta-Lesson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I realized: the conversation itself was demonstrating the productivity principle I needed to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of consuming more productivity content, I was actively working through my specific situation. Instead of generic advice, I was getting targeted questions. Instead of feeling judged for my limitations, I was finding ways to work with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversation was creation, not consumption. It was collaborative problem-solving in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-breakthrough-moment&#34;&gt;The Breakthrough Moment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real breakthrough came when we identified that the missing section of the app wasn&amp;rsquo;t just technically complicated - it was &amp;ldquo;lots of different pieces.&amp;rdquo; Suddenly the overwhelm made sense. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t one elegant problem to solve, but fifteen mini-features that all needed to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What if you just listed all the different pieces first? Not designing them, not coding them - just creating an inventory.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s when it clicked. The paralysis wasn&amp;rsquo;t about not knowing how to code. It was about not knowing where to start when everything felt connected to everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-this-means-for-productivity&#34;&gt;What This Means for Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best productivity hack might be finding someone who asks better questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not someone who gives you a system to follow. Not someone who tells you to eliminate distractions. Someone who helps you see your actual constraints clearly, then works with those constraints instead of ignoring them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generic productivity advice is like generic medical advice - it might work for some people, but it&amp;rsquo;s useless if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t account for your specific situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real productivity breakthrough happens when you stop trying to fit your life into someone else&amp;rsquo;s system and start building a system that fits your actual life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ironic-ending&#34;&gt;The Ironic Ending&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this conversation wanting to write about my productivity problems. I ended up actually solving them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blog post was supposed to be about the problem. Instead, it became about the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the most productive thing you can do is have a better conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2025/06/18/i-just-preordered-myself-a.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 12:56:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2025/06/18/i-just-preordered-myself-a.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just pre-ordered myself a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wildgym.com/pages/feather-ruck&#34;&gt;Feather Ruck&lt;/a&gt;. Grab one yourself while they are available. Only 500 of every color available for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2024/12/27/workout-day-today-triceps-shoulders.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 17:15:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2024/12/27/workout-day-today-triceps-shoulders.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Workout day. Today: triceps, shoulders and back again. They are my weak points and will need a few weeks of focus to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2024/12/24/sneaking-in-a-little-christmass.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 11:41:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2024/12/24/sneaking-in-a-little-christmass.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sneaking in a little Christmas’s workout before the festivities. Back, shoulders and triceps today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2024/10/04/today-is-fasting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 12:45:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2024/10/04/today-is-fasting.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is fasting day and also workout day. I need to get my arm back in shape after it got a hole the size of a tennis ball cut into my triceps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rope Jumping</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2024/09/21/rope-jumping.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 15:14:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2024/09/21/rope-jumping.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today marks the start of me getting back into rope jumping. I actually wanted to start rowing, but I have no space for a rowing machine right now and I refuse to pay gym fees just to get access to a rowing machine.
So rope jumping it will be for the foreseeable future. I just need to be uber-careful to start &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; slow to ease my joints into it. They do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; like sudden and prolonged strain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2024/09/03/with-my-whole.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 10:01:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2024/09/03/with-my-whole.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With my whole sebaceous gland inflammation episode I had to (or opted to) take a break from weightlifting. It’s been two months this now and I started back up &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; lightly last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is a workout day. Week 2, day 1. Still very light weights and high reps (~30).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m already feeling better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>