<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>2007s on Alexander Kucera</title>
    <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2007/</link>
    <description></description>
    
    <language>de</language>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 16:10:06 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Behave as New Guy - I Guess, I Wasn&#39;t the Only One</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2007/06/27/how-to-behave.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 16:10:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2007/06/27/how-to-behave.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just found an article on the BusinessWeek site entitled [“How Not to Be the Obnoxious Newcomer”] &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/careers/content/jun2007/ca20070607_981821.htm&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;.
It seems that author [Liz Ryan] &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/bios/Liz_Ryan.htm&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; has also stumbled over one too many of those annoying people that waltz in on their first day and step on everybody’s toes, just like I did a while ago when I wrote (link: blog/newbie_dont_act_like_a_pro text:“If you are a newbie, don’t act like a pro!”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz thinks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no doubt that every organization has a few best practices to share. As the new kid on the block, you can share what you’ve learned elsewhere and make a real contribution to your new employer’s operations. But if you lend that expertise in such a way that people roll their eyes and drift away when you enter a conversation, you’re not helping anyone—even worse, you’re setting yourself up to have negative credibility with your peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solo - a Danish Documentary</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2007/05/16/solo-a-danish.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2007 16:10:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2007/05/16/solo-a-danish.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone,
I have to make a completely selfish plug for a movie I worked on lately. It is called Solo and is about Jon, the first winner of the Danish Popstars show. I don’t speak a word of Danish — well, at least not enough to fully understand the movie — but the critics seem to love it and it is a big success for us so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me and my team worked on several things, some which made it into the final movie and some which ended up on the cutting floor. We had some nice effects and compositings in there, but the director decided that it is a documentary not an effects movie. A good decision if you ask me, although it is a pity the effects never me it into public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is left is a few name removals from signs and some other invisible effects to increase the quality of the material like degraining or resizing and reframing, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are shipping the DVD which has English subtitles (Yay! I finally can understand what I contributed to!!!) over the company website and through the normal DVD stores beginning of June. So just grab a copy and make the success even bigger, will ya?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Work Efficiently</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2007/04/10/how-to-work.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2007 16:10:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2007/04/10/how-to-work.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of times I hear people complaining how slow this or that program is. “shake is so slow”, “motion is total crap” or “why is this taking so long?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, guess what, there is actually a solution to it. And the magic word is &lt;em&gt;workflow&lt;/em&gt;. We are working on pretty heavy projects most of the time. HD material (even if the output will be PAL in the end), 2K material for film or lots of layers or 3D layers. All that stuff is by definition slow. Especially if you work in a more complex setup then one or two layers. Add to that, that we are working in a network based environment and you get a workflow slow as molasses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things you can to do help pretty much every program to work faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t work in full resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t turn on all the effects, just because it looks better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t work over the network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;THINK before you work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dont-work-in-full-resolution&#34;&gt;Don’t work in full resolution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know, you just built the most sexy motion graphics ever and you feel like looking at it over and over again, while tears run down your cheeks. Don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your first responsibility is to work as fast as you can, because that allows for making it even better and being more flexible when the customer has last minute changes. It is of little importance to look at your masterpiece in 100% resolution and highest quality most of the time. Don’t use these settings until you really need them to judge the final output quality. 
For all other cases go ahead and turn down the display size to 50% and the display quality to a third or a proxy of a third. Some applications even offer the option to go one step lower in quality as soon as you move things around. Use that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing you should think about is the use of proxies. A proxy is a lower resolution version of your footage. So instead of working on HD material you work on PAL or half PAL material. After Effects and shake both support the automatic use of proxies. That means they automatically switch from low-res to high-res version as needed.
To see how that is done, have a look at the tutorial video, that describes it in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dont-turn-on-all-the-effects-just-because-it-looks-better&#34;&gt;Don’t turn on all the effects, just because it looks better&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, that 3D lighting in AfterEffects is sexy. But if you are working on font sizes, it is absolutely irrelevant. So switch it off. Same goes for every other effect that slows you down, but has no effect on the part you are working on at the moment (Motion Blur, other kinds of blurs, re-timing, heavy 3D, particles, you name it). It is much faster to switch off 5 effects, do a change and switch them on again, then trying to make a change while waiting 5-10 seconds for the screen to update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dont-work-over-the-network&#34;&gt;Don’t work over the network&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might have a pretty fast network, but when 10-20 people work with HD or 2K footage over the network it slows down. Nothing that can be done about that. Except to copy your source material to a local drive. That will be way faster to work with then waiting for your bits and bytes to trickle through the cable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;think-before-you-work&#34;&gt;THINK before you work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems pretty obvious, right? Try to think before you start working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working locally is fast. But if it takes 2 hours to copy footage to make a 10 minute change, then it might not be the most efficient way of working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generating proxies is cool if you work on a shot for several hours or days. But generating proxies takes time as well. It might be faster to just open a file, do a quick change and render it out again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assess the situation and act accordingly. But don’t get lazy!! If you see a benefit, do it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter for Colloquy</title>
      <link>https://alexanderkucera.com/2007/01/28/twitter-for-colloquy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2007 16:10:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://AlexKucera.micro.blog/2007/01/28/twitter-for-colloquy.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if you already know this service called [Twitter] &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;. It can be described as a IM independent status message, so you can notify people of your current doings if you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Coda Hale] &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.codahale.com/&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; created a [Quicksilver action to post conveniently to Twitter] &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.codahale.com/2007/01/15/tweet-twitter-quicksilver/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;. [Ted Leung] &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sauria.com/blog/&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt; thought it would be nice to have [Growl notifications] &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sauria.com/blog/2007/01/18/growlified-tweet/&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt; in the mix and [Matt Matteson] &lt;a href=&#34;http://dlzip.com/wordpress/&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt; thought it needed a bit more sparkle by [adding iChat support] &lt;a href=&#34;http://dlzip.com/wordpress/2007/01/19/tweeter-twitter-quicksilver-ichat/&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;. Well, now I add two more options to the mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I created a modified version of Mattesons’ script to work with [Colloquy] &lt;a href=&#34;http://colloquy.info/&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt; — my favourite IRC chat client (Which I also use for IQC, MSN, Jabber and IRC via the help of [BitlBee] &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bitlbee.org/&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;). This worked out pretty straightforward and nice — and can be downloaded here (for setup instructions go to [Coda Hale’s page] &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.codahale.com/2007/01/15/tweet-twitter-quicksilver/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;). But then I thought it is stupid to have to change my status message of my chat client outside my chat client. So I sat down a little while longer and created a Colloquy script that posts to Twitter — including Growl notifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script works like the normal &lt;code&gt;/me&lt;/code&gt; commands in IRC but also posts the text behind the &lt;code&gt;/me&lt;/code&gt; command to Twitter. Users of Colloquy should know what it does, but for you non-IRC people, &lt;code&gt;/me&lt;/code&gt; creates an _action_ message so &lt;code&gt;/me is hungry&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;em&gt;AlexK (my nickname) is hungry&lt;/em&gt;. And on [Twitter] &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; it says _AlexK (my username there) is hungry_. It makes perfect sense (to me at least).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###How to install&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install it download this file, unpack it and save it as twitter.scpt into your Colloquy plugins folder (~/Library/Application Support/Colloquy/Plugins/twitter.scpt), then restart Colloquy (on some machines a system restart was necessary for unknown reasons).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you need to configure it. If you’re not already using [Twitterrific] &lt;a href=&#34;http://iconfactory.com/software/twitterrific/index.html&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;, open Keychain Access and add a new password with the following data:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keychain Item Name: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account Name: Your email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password: Your Twitter password&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re already using Twitterrific, this password will already be in your Keychain. So just sit tight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you can use it with the commands &lt;code&gt;/tweet&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;/twitter&lt;/code&gt; like so &lt;code&gt;/tweet is testing out this cool plugin&lt;/code&gt;. It should send and action message to your current chatroom (Nickname is testing out this cool plugin) and also to your Twitter account (Username is testing out this cool plugin). After it succeeded you will get a Growl notification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On first use you will be asked if it is ok that the script gets access to your Keychain. This is fine and you should allow that. On first usage it might also take a little bit longer, but from then on it should run pretty fast. At least it does so over here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###Caveats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have one guy who had problems with it running very slow (up to 15 seconds), but over here is runs pretty much realtime. Of course it has to send data over the internet, so that might be a slowdown factor. I guess if you like just try it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; [Jesse Newland] &lt;a href=&#34;http://soylentfoo.jnewland.com/&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt; linked the slowness to AppleScript needing a lot of time to access the Keychain in some cases. Maybe a bug on Apple’s side? Anyway he suggest to [use Rubygems to work around this] &lt;a href=&#34;http://soylentfoo.jnewland.com/articles/2007/01/22/tweet-update-twitter-via-quicksilver&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for that workaround, but I am not too hot on installing an extra piece of software just for this. But for all of you out there who have problems with my Colloquy/Twitter script being slow this might be a viable solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as always with this home-brewn scripts, I cannot give any guarantee that it works and I also distance myself from any damage done by it. It works great over here, but I cannot guarantee this for your setup. That is all I can say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###Following are comments from the old blog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blaine Says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice. It’s very cool to see twitter inching its way into every nook and cranny of the desktop and not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any particular reason you didn’t use Bitlbee’s Jabber integration to help you out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexander Kucera Says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, two reasons Blaine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hardly use Jabber these days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I use the Jabber route I am locked in to using Jabber&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explain the second one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say I am in an IRC channel. I’d have to switch the room to a Jabber connection to send my message to the twitter user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my script I am independent of the room I am in. It just intercepts the command and send it to Twitter. I don’t have to think about sending it to a specific user or anything else. I just type my command and it sends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very easy, very “out of my way”. I like to keep it simple, otherwise I end up not using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rinoa Says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found you on digg. Have you considered having your script submitted on the Colloquy website?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexander Kucera Says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Riona,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted it to be tested by a few more people before making it an “official” part of the Colloquy site. But yes, I am definitely thinking about submitting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blaine Says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That makes sense. I didn’t realize Bitlbee was presented as an independent room in IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep up the good work, and let us know (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:help@twitter.com&#34;&gt;help@twitter.com&lt;/a&gt;) if there’s anything we can do to improve twitter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>